<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='link' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
foobar
</title>
<link>
link
</link>
<description>
descriptionfoobar
</description>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<description>
There is a fascinating set of ideas that has been swirling around in the global zeitgeist for the past decade, around the quote that will keep Donald Rumsfeld in the history books long after his political career is forgotten. I am referring, of course, to the famous unknown-unknowns quote from 2002. Here it is: [T]here are [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 22 Mar 2012 16:38:18 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Can Hydras Eat Unknown-Unknowns for Lunch?
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/Vrs1qjMuEyc/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3170
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Pondering the A. G. Lafley HBR piece that&amp;#8217;s been doing the rounds lately, I think I&amp;#8217;ve finally really figured out the difference between managers, leaders and workers. The title, and this cartoon I made up, capture the essence of my argument: all three archetypes within the world of business are defined by how they self-destruct. This [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 23 Jun 2009 00:35:53 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Neurotic Leaders, Paternalistic Managers and Self-Absorbed Workers
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/HuPX5MiuBQ0/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=1057
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
For my fourth video blog, I bring you a wide-ranging conversation with David Bosshart, CEO of the Gottlieb Duttweiler Institute (GDI) in Zurich. I&amp;#8217;ve known the folks at GDI for a few years, and worked with them several times. Most recently, GDI undertook the German translation of my Breaking Smart essays. This conversation is partly me interviewing [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 18 Oct 2016 14:29:16 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Can the European Union Break Smart?
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/3YvtmrD9Bp4/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=5642
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
This is a guest post by Craig Roche, a data scientist and artisanal landlord. Whiskey is very easy to make.  Farmers used to make it at home using their crops, and Henry Ford designed the Model T to run on home-distilled ethanol.  George Washington distilled 55,000 bottles/year when he retired from being President. Even the mutineers [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 30 Sep 2014 13:26:18 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Political Hangover of Prohibition
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/gONM7UjTWLA/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4761
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Kevin is a 2013 blogging resident visiting us from his home blog over at Melting Asphalt. To scandalize a member of the educated West, open any book on European table manners from the middle of the second millennium: &amp;#8220;Some people gnaw a bone and then put it back in the dish. This is a serious offense.&amp;#8221; — Tannhäuser, 13th century. &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 07 Nov 2013 13:41:09 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
UX and the Civilizing Process
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/rdktYk_JK9E/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4388
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Sarah Perry is a contributing editor of Ribbonfarm. Nouns for human beings &amp;#8211; &amp;#8220;people&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;person&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; conjure in the mind a snapshot of the surface appearance of humans. Using nouns like &amp;#8220;people&amp;#8221; subtly encourages thinking about people as frozen in time, doing nothing in particular. &amp;#8220;People&amp;#8221; is an anchor for thinking about human bodies [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 08 Apr 2015 11:00:13 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Essence of Peopling
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/zBGJqZZk-Jk/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4930
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
We’ve been told for years now that what our parents and kindergarten teachers told us is not, in fact, true — we are not each and every one of us special unique snowflakes destined for greatness. In this essay I want to offer a new theory of productivity for those of us who, despite all the evidence [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 28 Jan 2016 16:17:07 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Productivity for Precious Snowflakes
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/fUB6Dwr1LrI/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=5296
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Since it&amp;#8217;s been more than week since my last post, I thought I&amp;#8217;d do a quick meta-post for those of you who don&amp;#8217;t follow my off-ribbonfarm blogging gigs. The next original ribbonfarm post will have to wait till next week, since I am in the middle of a rather hectic trip. So here are two [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:33:11 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Neatness, Organization and Unsociability
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/26RKTLoPmJg/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=875
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting lately with aphorisms. Pithy one-liners of the sort favored by writers like La Rochefoucauld (1613-1680). My goal was to turn a relatively big idea, the sort I would normally turn into a 4000-word post, into a one-liner. After many failed attempts over the last few months, a few weeks ago, I finally managed to [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 03 May 2012 20:28:58 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Rediscovering Literacy
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/t1kKa7BI3oI/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3238
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Of all the seductive ideas in psychology, none is more dangerous than the idea that one is free. Humans have a tendency to jump to conclusions on the matter, on the basis of the flimsiest of evidence. We also believe that freedom is fragile. So humans who do suspect they are free are usually reluctant to advertise the [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 08 Aug 2013 19:52:45 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
On Freedomspotting
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/Je1vcPYVNUw/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4225
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
For the last six months, the scarcity/abundance dichotomy has been annoying me.  All dichotomies are false of course, but some are more of a bitch to transcend than others. On a 10-point scale where good vs. evil is a 4 in terms of transcendence difficulty, I&amp;#8217;d rate scarcity versus abundance at 8.5. And it is [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 23 Aug 2012 02:30:21 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Waste, Creativity and Godwin’s Corollary for Technology
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/b2gng8VFzjY/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3472
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Time for a roundup and Labor-Day long-read fodder for some of you. It&amp;#8217;s been a summer of fairly ambitious posts for me. Besides finally finishing up the Gervais Principle series, I managed one usual-ribbonfarm-bag-of-tricks post (#8) and three that strike out in a new and somewhat difficult new direction of thinking/writing for me (#4, #10, #11). Residents [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 28 Aug 2013 13:45:36 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Roundup, May-August 2013, September in Bay Area, Sponsorship Update
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/RMG7f8eRGdI/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4257
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Sarah Perry is a resident blogger visiting us from her home turf at The View from Hell. A selective sweep occurs when a new, beneficial gene mutation appears and quickly sweeps across a population, erasing the genetic diversity that existed prior to the sweep. Similarly, languages have &amp;#8220;swept&amp;#8221; across continents as the cultures they belonged [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 08 Jan 2015 11:24:03 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Ritual and the Consciousness Monoculture
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/hhSUTDO_xTA/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4854
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
A quick announcement. I&amp;#8217;ll be in Los Angeles on Tuesday the 27th to do a talk at the USC Annenberg Innovation Lab titled Should You Drink the Kool-Aid? The talk is at 12:30 PM at Annenberg (which appears to be in the heart of downtown). Details at the link above.  Hope to see some of you [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Fri, 23 Nov 2012 14:27:16 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Talk on Kool Aid, VUCA Discussion, Tuesday Nov 27 at USC (Los Angeles)
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/CotSj_90Gf4/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3627
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
I&amp;#8217;ve been procrastinating on this post for a couple of weeks, wondering what the heck to say about my first attempt at a serious Ribbonfarm event: Refactor Camp 2012, on March 3rd, at the San Francisco Zoo. Throughout 2011, I did a whole lot of physical-world stuff, meeting people all over the country, sleeping on [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 14 Mar 2012 21:32:27 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Reviewing Refactor Camp 2012
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/JVgVLk8XoO0/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3150
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
A few months ago, I read a thoroughly depressing book by V. Raghunathan, Games Indians Play: Why We Are the Way We Are. That book is a game-theoretic exploration of Indian weaknesses.  Being a strengths-oriented guy, I am offering up  a much more energizing look at real Indian games and what they reveal [...]&lt;img src=&quot;http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~4/272644153&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:53:40 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Other Games Indians Play
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/272644153/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2008/04/17/the-other-games-indians-play/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
After months of procrastination, I&amp;#8217;ve finally managed to put together the promised ebooks of the Gervais Principle series ($3.99 on Kindle in the US) and the archives of the Be Slightly Evil email list ($2.99 on Kindle in the US), which I&amp;#8217;ve officially retired as of last week. I will also be conducting the Gervais Principle online workshop [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 25 Sep 2013 13:33:46 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Rough Books for Roughening School
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/8HG-ioUPS94/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4324
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
The story of barbed wire is one of the most instructive ones in the history of technology.  The short version is this: barbed wire (developed between 1860 to 1873) helped close the American frontier, carved out the killing fields of World War I, and by spurring the development of the tank as a counter-weapon, created [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 16 Aug 2012 21:56:49 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Realtechnik, Nausea and Technological Longing
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/pUpFTCUAwjI/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3289
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Occasionally, I manage to be clever when I am not even trying to be clever, which isn&amp;#8217;t often. In a recent conversation about the new class of doomsday scenarios inspired by AlphaGo beating the Korean trash-talker Lee Sedol, I came up with the phrase human complete (HC) to characterize certain kinds of problems: the hardest problems of being human. [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 31 Mar 2016 19:28:55 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Human-Complete Problems
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/EZId9DIi5rI/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=5422
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
I have this comic fantasy of some day being in a business situation where a client comes to me with a tricky problem. I ponder impassively for a moment. Then I pick up the phone and make one cryptic phone call. I then look at the client and say, &amp;#8220;Go home, it will be taken [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 12 Sep 2013 16:54:55 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Exercise of Authoritah
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/8wuAFqumdzA/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4275
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Over the Thanksgiving weekend, I tried, and failed, to relax. I am sure I am not alone, and that many of you had the same experience. But I failed in a very revealing way, that led me a very interesting definition of work. What happened was this: I was reading a book to relax (Robert [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 29 Nov 2010 17:48:27 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
What Does it Mean to Work Hard?
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/t0cZ0XjYfWU/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=2175
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Both science fiction and futurism seem to miss an important piece of how the future actually turns into the present. They fail to capture the way we don&amp;#8217;t seem to notice when the future actually arrives. Sure, we can all see the small clues all around us: cellphones, laptops, Facebook, Prius cars on the street. [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 09 May 2012 20:37:49 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Welcome to the Future Nauseous
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/yXA14OYxxss/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3260
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
A few days ago, in the course of some routine correspondence at work with a colleague at another company, I noticed his email signature: &amp;#8220;Win Over Others &amp;#124; Communication &amp;#124; Strategic &amp;#124; Analytical &amp;#124; Activator.&amp;#8221; In my reply, I included a postscript, &amp;#8220;p.s.: I&amp;#8217;d be Intellection&amp;#124; Strategic &amp;#124; Input &amp;#124; Context &amp;#124; Ideation.&amp;#8221; If this [...]&lt;img src=&quot;http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~4/270719145&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 15 Apr 2008 09:37:52 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Coming Triumph of the Strengths Movement
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/270719145/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2008/04/15/the-coming-triumph-of-the-strengths-movement/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
A couple of weeks ago, after reading yet another piece of high-minded marketing copy, full of words like hand-crafted and artisan, a silly verse popped unbidden into my head: This is not the renaissance. You are not an artisan. Go around to the back door, you&amp;#8217;re a smelly tradesman.  So long as we&amp;#8217;re pretending that we&amp;#8217;re rediscovering [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 10 Jul 2013 01:49:08 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
You Are Not an Artisan
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/dYaFlDfsD4s/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4097
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Guest post by Drew Austin of Kneeling Bus, an excellent blog about urbanism and cities.  Although connectedness is the spirit of the city, and will probably remain so, the American version has always harbored a tendency to explode, to atomize, and to spread itself as far as possible. Today this may be exacerbated (or made [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 23 Oct 2012 14:45:38 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Navigating the Holey Plane
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/9Ru9vk5RghQ/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3575
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Distance metaphors are natural in any conversation about social phenomena. We talk of the distance between governance systems and the governed, guerrilla movements and host populations,  rich and poor, Chinese and American, Red and Blue. Kevin Simler&amp;#8217;s recent guest post made use of the standard geometric-metaphoric scheme, the Hofstede cultural dimensions model, to talk about startup cultures. The [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 19 Nov 2012 21:26:37 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Notes on Spatial Metaphors for Social Systems
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/Sux-mFQijZc/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3617
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
There is a fascinating set of ideas that has been swirling around in the global zeitgeist for the past decade, around the quote that will keep Donald Rumsfeld in the history books long after his political career is forgotten. I am referring, of course, to the famous unknown-unknowns quote from 2002. Here it is: [T]here are [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 22 Mar 2012 16:38:18 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Can Hydras Eat Unknown-Unknowns for Lunch?
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/Vrs1qjMuEyc/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3170
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
The full title of this book, Spanning Silos: The New CMO Imperative, might lead you to believe that it is a very narrow take on a particular organizational issue (silos) within one enterprise function (marketing). You&amp;#8217;d be wrong. This is a wolf-in-sheep&amp;#8217;s-clothing book; a book about foundational issues in organization theory masquerading as a specialist [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Fri, 14 Nov 2008 20:18:46 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Spanning Silos by David Aaker
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/Jvu29a1RJuo/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=595
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
There is a saying that goes back to Milo of Croton: lift a calf everyday and when you grow up, you can lift a cow. The story goes that Milo, a famous wrestler in ancient Greece, gained his immense strength by lifting a newborn calf one day when he was a boy, and then lifting [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Fri, 23 Sep 2011 16:00:26 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Milo Criterion
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/4nMJCqSFgd4/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=1937
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
This is a guest post by Mike Travers, who develops software at Collaborative Drug Discovery, blogs on diverse topics at Omniorthogonal, collects his random hacks at Hyperphor, and has a PhD in Media Arts and Sciences. The scientific picture of the world has some disturbing implications when its assumptions are worked out to their ultimate conclusions. Brains and bodies [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:57:00 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Patterns of Refactored Agency
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/U2aJYXlIVd4/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3630
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
News flash: I was just interviewed (you can listen here) along with David Allen, the man himself, about this article, by Karen Hammer at KGNU. If any listeners found their way here after the show, welcome to ribbonfarm! If you are interested in having some fun organizing your life, you might want to send in [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 08 Jan 2009 00:36:19 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Allenism, Taylorism and the Day I Rode the Thundercloud
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/PdquruNh6ys/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=748
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Twitter It!

This is a guest post by Dorian Taylor, with whom I&amp;#8217;ve been having a thought-provoking Twitter conversation about design. Here is an interesting pecha-kucha talk by Dorian that kinda explains where he&amp;#8217;s coming from.

When I first en­coun­tered the phrase min­imum vi­able prod­uct, I thought to my­self here is a term that is ripe for [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 01 Mar 2010 08:02:37 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
The Expedient, Desirable Product
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/03pRWjgFFyA/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=1553
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
When I had my first mid-life crisis at age 17, I really didn&amp;#8217;t know how to handle it. I went from sociable and friendly to morose and uncommunicative overnight, and stayed that way for a year. Now, 24 years later, I am getting really good at navigating them. I predicted 11 of my last 5 [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 17 Dec 2015 18:03:43 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
We Are All Architects Now
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/zswpM89kpUo/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=5233
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Several recent discussions on a variety of unrelated topics with different people have gotten me thinking about two different attitudes towards dialectical processes. They are generalized versions of the professional attitudes  required of lawyers and judges, so I&amp;#8217;ll refer to them as lawyer mind and judge mind.  In the specialized context of the law, the dialectical [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 29 Mar 2012 00:59:45 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Lawyer Mind, Judge Mind
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/XDZ-0kHqMWA/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3187
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
A couple of weeks ago, I was introduced to the bitcoin-based tipping service for Twitter, ChangeTip, by Leslie John Dilley. It is a fascinating thing to experiment with, and you should try it out if you&amp;#8217;re interested in bitcoin. What makes it particularly interesting is that you can define your own pseudo-currency units called &amp;#8220;monikers&amp;#8221;. [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 02 Dec 2014 17:56:34 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
The Future of Tipping
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/cRIQJ5MhVCI/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4829
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
On the weekend of March 2 and 3, we will be organizing the second annual Refactor Camp. The theme for Refactor Camp 2013: Jailbreaking the Bay Area. The event will be held at the San Francisco zoo, same as last year. Regular tickets are $75 and sponsoring attendee tickets are $150.  The ticket includes lunch [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 28 Jan 2013 15:40:00 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Jailbreaking the City: Announcing Refactor Camp 2013
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/G3qWO1dP_sw/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=3773
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
This is a guest post by Brian Potter of  Coarse Grained. It explores a different aspect of some of the ideas in my post, The Return of the Barbarian, and Paula Hay&amp;#8217;s guest post, Cognitive Archeology of the West. If you are interested in guest-posting, email me. Consider the following experiment (the Wason selection task): [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 21 Apr 2011 13:43:40 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Russian Fox and the Evolution of Intelligence
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/y2QGuCmyQMc/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=2459
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
The Tristate area Refactorings meetup group is holding its monthly meetup in New York, on Wednesday (the 12th) at Pete&amp;#8217;s Tavern at 6:30 PM. The group has been active online and offline for about six months now, thanks to the efforts of Jay Hinton and Adam Hogan, and I am looking forward to finally meeting [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 11 Jun 2013 08:27:45 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
New York City Meetup on Wednesday, 12th June
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/rHstEQZp4uU/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4122
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Talk about a recession. Ribbonfarm is off to a very slow start in 2009, going by posting frequency. Between January 1 and May 5, I wrote a total of just 15 posts. Or less than a post a week. In 2008, I was posting twice as frequently, with 80 posts, or about 1.5 posts a [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 05 May 2009 23:34:36 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Ribbonfarm at the Crossroads
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/CmSz5u6v-wE/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=973
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Twitter It!July 4th will be the three-year anniversary of Ribbonfarm. I normally celebrate with a retrospective-plus-roundup, but this year, I thought I&amp;#8217;d do something different. I am not entirely sure what you guys get out of my writing, but for me, the act of writing this blog has clarified, reinforced and (for better or worse) [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 30 Jun 2010 14:05:08 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Philosopher’s Abacus
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/ecOH0XhUORw/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=1854
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Imagine that there is a mystery closed curve about the origin. Allow two parallel lines to approach the origin from diametrically opposed directions, and have them stop where they first become tangent to the mystery curve. Suppose you do this from all pairs of directions from (0,π) to (π,0), and find that the lines stop [...]&lt;img src=&quot;http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~4/246592294&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 06 Mar 2008 01:54:59 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
The UnAha! Experience
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/246592294/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2008/03/05/unaha/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Twitter It!My neighbor introduced me to The Office back in 2005. Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve watched every episode of both the British and American versions. I&amp;#8217;ve watched the show obsessively because I&amp;#8217;ve been unable to figure out what makes it so devastatingly effective, and elevates it so far above the likes of Dilbert and Office Space.  [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 07 Oct 2009 22:56:17 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Gervais Principle, Or The Office According to “The Office”
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/qUeM0qdplZg/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=1289
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Kartik is a 2014 blogging resident visiting us from his home turf at akkartik.name. I am fascinated by organizations as a technology for agency transfer &amp;#8212; getting people to follow some plan outside of their selves. We’re not yet very good at building such agency transformers; our organizations get gamed, taken over, taken advantage of, [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 09 Apr 2014 19:05:45 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Legibility Tradeoff
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/GYuv1a9dtLg/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4625
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Mike is a 2013 blogging resident visiting us from his home blog Omniorthogonal. This series of posts has explored a variety of ways in which agency – the ability of something to initiate action – can be rethought, redistributed, and refactored. Agency can be assigned to things that normally don’t have it, or we can undo our everyday [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 17 Dec 2013 13:44:37 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Morality for Exploded Minds
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/tDjLd5voYTg/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4453
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Twitter It!In Omaha, I was asked this question multiple times: &amp;#8220;Err&amp;#8230; why do you want to go to North Platte?&amp;#8221; Each time, my wife explained, with a hint of embarrassment, that we were going to see Bailey Yard. &amp;#8220;He saw this thing on the Discovery Channel about the world&amp;#8217;s largest train yard&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; A kindly, somewhat [...]
</description>
<pubDate>
Sun, 07 Mar 2010 23:29:26 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
An Infrastructure Pilgrimage
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/IQ6TW3DnDl4/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=1556
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
I have my second essay up at Aeon Magazine, Deep Play. It&amp;#8217;s an attempt at an impressionistic picture of how the world of innovation works.  Here&amp;#8217;s an extract: The EMP Museum, the Gates Foundation, and the MOHAI form what I’ve dubbed the Titan Triangle of Seattle, a zone of violent urban terraforming. Sometimes, on my walks, [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 19 Nov 2013 22:04:27 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Deep Play: An Impressionistic Theory of Innovation
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/ibiaml5EwC0/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4423
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Here&amp;#8217;s the complete roundup for 2015 in chronological order. New readers this year might want to check out the 2014 roundup and 2013 roundup. If you want to do some binge reading further back into the archives, there is a page for the Rust Age (2007-12) with both curated selections and complete roundups. This year we released an [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 23 Dec 2015 15:26:29 -0500
</pubDate>
<title>
Complete 2015 Roundup
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/GgojRKXk13A/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=5270
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Kevin is a 2013 blogging resident visiting us from his home blog over at Melting Asphalt. How can &amp;#8216;mere&amp;#8217; matter, properly configured, manage to be conscious? Are chimpanzees or elephants conscious? Can a computer be conscious? Today we will answer none of these questions. In fact, we won&amp;#8217;t even address them. These questions probe what David Chalmers calls, [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 01 Jul 2013 13:08:18 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Consciousness: An Outside View
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/2heCLAyG50I/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4157
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
Sarah Perry is a contributing editor of Ribbonfarm. Why do some stories become popular, retold for hundreds of years, while others are forgotten? Why do you see the particular stories that you see in your social media feed and on the news? How can we tell whether stories are true? And why are false stories [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Thu, 02 Jun 2016 15:48:39 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
The Theory of Narrative Selection
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/MUZXl1u7PJc/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=5479
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<description>
It&amp;#8217;s been a busy few weeks for me. Since I just returned from three weeks in Chile and am still catching my breath, you get a roundup instead of new material this week. We&amp;#8217;ve had 16 posts so far this year: four from Sarah, two from Haley, one from Ryan and nine from me. The [&amp;#8230;]
</description>
<pubDate>
Fri, 01 May 2015 10:41:43 -0400
</pubDate>
<title>
Roundup: January – April 2015
</title>
<link>
http://feeds.ribbonfarm.com/~r/Ribbonfarm/~3/M7XjJ4On4BY/
</link>
<guid>
http://www.ribbonfarm.com/?p=4950
</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
